Ganeev Singh

SAN FRANCISCO, CA 94133
HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/GANEEVSINGH

PERSONAL PROFILE

For most of my life, I have been fascinated by the field of medicine and my last two years of college allowed me to explore the business sector as well. After graduating with honors from UCLA, I moved up to San Francisco to work as an Associate Consultant at a healthcare consulting firm. As an aspiring physician (MD/MBA/MPH) with an extensive medical background and strong management skills, I will be able to become a doctor who runs healthcare entrepreneurship ventures on the side that benefit not just the elite, but people of limited means who have nowhere to turn to for help. I am also interested in higher level hospital management, running multiple hospitals one day and impacting lives in my community and beyond.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Psychobiology, minor in Entrepreneurship

September 2013 – June 2017

University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA), Los Angeles, CA

• College Honors & Magna Cum Laude Latin Honors (Cumulative GPA: 3.82)

Certificate in Patient Experience and Pre-Licensed Clinical Care

February 2017 - May 2017

University of California, Los Angeles - Fielding School of Public Health, Los Angeles, CA

PUBLICATIONS

Dagnew, R., Lin, Y., Agatep, J., Cheng, M., Jann, A., Quach, V., Monroe, M., **Singh, G.**, Minasyan, A., Hakimian, J., Kee, T., Cushman, J., & Walwyn, W. (2017). "CerebraLux: A low cost, open source, wireless probe for optogenetic stimulation." *Neurophotonics*, 4(4) 045001.

Severino, A., Shadfar, A., Hakimian, J., Crane, O., **Singh, G.**, Heinzerling, K., & Walwyn, W. (2018). *Pain therapy guided by purpose and perspective in light of the opioid epidemic*. Manuscript submitted for publication.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT | TRIAGE CONSULTING GROUP, SAN FRANCISCO, CA

August 2017 - Present

- Identify systematic payment discrepancies in the hospital revenue cycle by manipulating large sets of patient data
- Compile project results into client deliverables to provide risk analysis, revenue cycle improvement suggestions, and contract negotiation recommendations
- Interact with hospital clients and Triage's upper management to perform reviews and communicate project results
- Perform comprehensive audits of thousands of accounts to effectively filter data and uncover underlying trends
- Contact insurance companies with written appeals in extensive legal language to recover payments for hospital clients
- Collaborate on a team of 12 people to develop an efficient organizational workflow
- Continually analyze and quality-control underpayment risk areas to ensure audit accuracy
- Participate in Triage's recruiting and training programs, periodic team-building events, and socially responsible activities

INTERN | CAPRICOR THERAPEUTICS INC., BEVERLY HILLS, CA

April 2017 – June 2017

Produced market research reports on existing and potential indications to help guide clinical and business decisions

FINANCIAL REPRESENTATIVE INTERN | NORTHWESTERN MUTUAL, LOS ANGELES, CA

January 2016 - November 2016

- Consulted with clients to determine financial goals, and offered research-based advice to meet clients' needs
- Developed clients' comprehensive financial plans regarding investment portfolios and insurance needs
- Continuously networked and built individual client base, through referred prospecting and LinkedIn outreach
- Invited to be a part of the Northwestern Mutual iLead top intern program to hone leadership skills

OPERATIONS COORDINATOR | ARBORBRIDGE, LOS ANGELES, CA

January 2016 - June 2016

- Initiated comprehensive income and expense analyses that contributed to the acquisition of another company
- Identified areas for improvement in business processes and delivered strategic recommendations to senior management
- Handled inquiries through quality customer care and liaised with cross-functional teams in support of customer needs

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH ASSISTANT | UCLA HATOS RESEARCH CENTER FOR NEUROPHARMACOLOGY

November 2014 - July 2017

- Spearheaded independent experiments to understand chronic neuropathic pain and opiate/cocaine addiction
- Operated on mice to surgically implant optic fibers in key areas of their brains for optogenetic experiments
- · Performed subcutaneous and intravenous injections on mice during drug addiction experiments
- Conducted DNA cloning, sequencing, and mapping of the D1 and D2 brain pathways using qPCR and gel electrophoresis

HEALTH SCHOLAR | COPE HEALTH SOLUTIONS AT ADVENTIST HEALTH GLENDALE, GLENDALE, CA

February 2017 - June 2017

- Assisted medical staff members in preparing and positioning patients for procedures by performing direct patient care
- Independently positioned telemetry leads, ambulated, and fed patients upon RN approval
- Assisted in performing post-mortem care
- Shadowed nurses, physicians, and healthcare professionals to observe medical procedures in a sterile environment
- Assisted the department's unit secretary with paperwork, answering phones, and answering patient call lights as needed
- Coordinated communication between patients, family members, medical professionals, and administrative staff

PATIENT TRANSPORT | RONALD REAGAN UCLA MEDICAL CENTER

February 2017 - June 2017

Transported patients and visitors to and from procedure rooms, patient rooms, and the hospital lobby

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

UNDERGRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT | UCLA DEPARTMENT OF CHEMISTRY & BIOCHEMISTRY

April 2017 - June 2017

• Facilitated students' learning of organic chemistry through the development of organic chemistry teaching modules on BACON (Biology and Chemistry Online Notes and Tutorials). BACON connects organic chemistry to health and pop culture

OPERATIONS COMMITTEE | UCLA BRUIN MEDICAL ENTREPRENEURS

January 2017 - June 2017

Managed the operations of the organization (e.g. building a quarterly calendar and running weekly events)

RESIDENT ASSISTANT | UCLA RESIDENTIAL LIFE

September 2014 – June 2017

- Developed and implemented proactive educational and community building programs
- Served on-call regularly for emergency and crisis response in a community of over 1000 residents
- Trained to assist EMS, University Police, Campus Safety Officers, and University Fire Department
- Coordinated opportunities for team development with the professional staff

MARKETING DIRECTOR | UCLA BHAGAT PURAN SINGH HEALTH INITIATIVE

September 2014 – June 2017

- Assessed more than 100 patients and recorded BMI, blood glucose levels, blood pressure, and other health data
- Led a group of 30 student activists in health awareness campaigns and free medical aid clinics at local churches
- Created compelling presentations for organization meetings on topics such as healthy eating habits and effective communicative techniques for spreading health education in the community

HONORS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

Guiding Principles Award Nomination, *Triage Consulting Group*UCLA Phi Beta Kappa Honors Society, *UCLA*UCLA College Honors, *UCLA*Exemplary Service Award, *COPE Health Solutions*Staff Scholar, *UCLA Residential Life*UCLA True Bruin Distinguished Senior Award Finalist, *UCLA*Dean's Honors List, *UCLA*UCLA Achievement Scholarship, *UCLA*UCLA Alumni Scholarship, *UCLA*

June 2017 June 2017 February 2017 November 2016 Spring 2014 – Spring

December 2017

June 2017

Spring 2014 – Spring 2017 2013 – 2017

2013 – 2017 2013 – 2017 October 2014

SKILLS

Software: Advanced proficiency in MS Office Suite; Basic proficiency in QuickBooks, Photoshop, HTML, CSS, and Java **Foreign Languages:** Advanced fluency in Hindi and Urdu

Certifications and Licenses: AHA Basic Life Support for Healthcare Professionals Certification

Team Recognition Award, UCLA Residential Life